Sujith PV

Manager Technology at Sapient

Summary

Sujith PV is a Technology Manager at Sapient's Bangalore office. Before joining Sapient, Sujith has developed and delivered websites, intranets and extranets in .NET Technologies. He has expertise in CMS like Umbraco and SharePoint.

Sujith has sound knowledge of technologies including .NET Framework 2.0/3.5/4.0, ASP.NET, C#, WSS 3.0, MOSS 2007, Umbraco, Sql Server Reporting Service, Sql Server Integration Service and Web Services.

Specialties: ASP.NET 1.1/2.0/3.5/4.0 with C#.

ASP.NET MVC

WCF, Web Services, REST

Web API

SQL Server 2005/2008

Javascript, Ajax, JQuery

SharePoint 2007

BI Dashboards

Performance Point Server

SSIS,SSAS and SSRS

Sharepoint (WSS,MOSS).

Umbraco (Open source CMS based on .NET)

StyleCop

Moq

MbUnit

Gallio Automation Platform

Rhino ETL

Experience

Manager Technology at Sapient

January 2017 - Present (3 months)

Senior Associate Technology L2 at Sapient

August 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Currently working in Tesco account in retail domain with the Grocery team.

Senior Associate Technology L1 at Sapient

February 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 7 months)

Senior Web Developer at Software Associates

April 2007 - February 2012 (4 years 11 months)

Skills & Expertise

ASP.NET

Web Services

Microsoft SQL Server

WCF

jQuery

C#

JavaScript

ASP.NET MVC

SharePoint

Windows Sharepoint Services

MVC

REST

Windows Communication Foundation (WCF)

SSRS

Umbraco

AJAX

Microsoft Office Sharepoint Server

SSIS

Web API

Moq

MbUnit

Rhino ETL

.NET

Requirements Analysis

ASP.NET AJAX

Gallio

Node.js

IOT

Arduino

Entity Framework

JSON

.NET Framework

Web Services API

Docker

Riemann

InfluxDb

Grafana

Red Hat Linux

Varnish Caching

SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS)

Representational State Transfer (REST)

SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS): .NET Framework 3.5, ASP.NET Applications

Microsoft License 7688938

MCTS: .NET Framework 4, Service Communication Applications

Microsoft License 7688938

AppDynamics in Action for Operators

APPDYNAMICS University

Education

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

MS Software Systems, Software Systems, 2010 - 2012

DOEACC

PGDST, .NET and Java technologies, 2006 - 2006

NSS College of Engineering Palakkad

Btech Electronics & Communication Engineering, Electronics & Communication, 2001 - 2005

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya Malappuram

1993 - 2000

Interests

Web Development, Research

Honors and Awards

You make a difference

Sapient

March 2016

Your are being recognized for diligence in delivery excellence, acquiring skills for business success and challenging the status quo.

Thank you for setting a great example

Coolest IoT Application Award (BARCAMP - IV)

Sapient

April 2016

SmartBin - Winner

Presented to Sujith PV for meeting the challenge with determination, strength and total confidence. With enthusiasm and hard work like yours, success was certain to be achieved. Well done. Congratulations on this wonderful achievement.

Client-Focused Delivery

Sapient

January 2013

Create fanatical advocates for Sapient by providing extraordinary experiences and unprecedented outcomes for our clients and their customers.

HACKME 2.0 Winner at Sapient

Sapient

February 2017

You are a 'samurai' now for winning the newFUNdamentals war. Congratulations SUJITH P V . Your way, the warrior way begins now !

Volunteer Experience

Volunteer at Prayaas (Sapient)

September 2016 - Present

Lighten Up Someone's Diwali

Languages

English

Malayalam(Native or bilingual proficiency)Hindi(Limited working proficiency)Tamil(Limited working proficiency)

Sujith PV

Manager Technology at Sapient



3 people have recommended Sujith

"Sujith has always been the mature, responsible and dependent member in my team at Sapient. His calm and meticulous way of working even in the most complex situations at the client office has been his most important positive point. Planned, organized and dedicated to his goals he has grown in the organization from a new joining team member to a person whom people go to for advise. Project related work, additional initiatives or any special assignments he has always been active to take up responsibility and deliver positive measurable results. A result oriented and dependable person, an asset to any team and organization that he is a part. I am very happy to have worked with Sujith and with great pleasure would like to recommend him."

— Amit Toshniwal, PMP®, CSM®, managed Sujith at Sapient

"Sujith is a pleasure to work with because of his can do attitude and never hesitant to go that extra mile. He is always looking for better ways to accomplish and deliver the best possible output. He always keeps himself updated with the latest technological developments. He is very competent professional and follows "The tech" religion very seriously. He is superb at achieving goals before time and is a fine team player. Highly recommended .."

— Karn Singh, worked directly with Sujith at Sapient

"If you ask me for a person with equal command over technology and client requirement understanding, I will definitely recommend Sujith. As a marketing manager at Software Associates, I was not only impressed by his knowledge of ASP .net and Umbraco, but also by the fact that Sujith was able to foresee solutions for the clients using these technologies. I mean, anyone can write few lines of code, but giving it a human thought process, one should learn from Sujith. Last but not the least, Sujith is a very well natured person, and a good friend to all. I would definitely remember the time we spent togather at Software Associates."

— Sheetanshu Shekhar, worked directly with Sujith at Software Associates

Contact Sujith on LinkedIn